<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <title>Commandline Options</title>

<para><variablelist>
<varlistentry><term><anchor id="cmdopt_1_cmdopt000001"/>Global <link linkend="classorg_1_1smallfoot_1_1vw4_1_1VirtualWisdom4ClientTool_1a75988cf84fc6ee7a2ebff36e363021aa">VirtualWisdom4ClientTool.main</link>  (String args[])</term>
<listitem>
<para>-H|&#8211;help Show a simple help screen as a reminder of options which are understood by the application </para>

<para><programlisting>java&#32;-jar&#32;vw4tools.jar&#32;--help&#32;
</programlisting></para>

<para>-V|&#8211;version Show the current release version for reference </para>

<para><programlisting>java&#32;-jar&#32;vw4tools.jar&#32;--version
&#32;0.9-91&#32;
</programlisting></para>

<para>-n|&#8211;nicknameout={file} Output nicknames from internal store </para>

<para>-o|&#8211;output={file} Output nicknames from internal store &#8211;nicknameout and &#8211;output are currently functionally identical; they both cause the internal nickname/entity base to be written out as JSON with the exception of a few &quot;magic&quot; filenames:</para>

<para>1. <emphasis role="bold">schema.json</emphasis> will cause the current schema to be written </para>

<para>2. <emphasis role="bold">orderedtuples.csv</emphasis> will cause an OrderedTuples.csv file to be written, suitable for post-processing via <link linkend="csv-to-json_8awk">csv-to-json.awk</link> but allowing a user to more easily edit CSV for fine-tuning </para>

<para>3. <emphasis role="bold">orphanentities.csv</emphasis> will cause a CSV to be written listing all orphan entities. An &quot;Orphan Entity&quot; is an entity lacking a parent entity, such as an &quot;HBA Port&quot; without a &quot;host&quot; parent, or a &quot;iomodule&quot; without a parent &quot;storagearray&quot; entity.</para>

<para>All other filename patterns will result in a JSON-formatted file</para>

<para>-N|&#8211;nickname={file/uri} Import nicknames by parsing a text stream from various sources </para>

<para><programlisting>java&#32;-jar&#32;vw4tools.jar&#32;--nickname=switch44.zoneshow
&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;Parse&#32;results&#32;<emphasis>for</emphasis>&#32;AliShowZoneParser:
&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;Zones:&#32;44
&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;Aliases:&#32;112&#32;(names&#32;with&#32;one&#32;or&#32;more&#32;WWPNs)
&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;Aliases:&#32;136&#32;(name/WWPN&#32;tuples)&#32;
</programlisting> In this example, a zone file was parsed by the AliShowZoneParser resulting in 112 nicknames; due to duplicate nicknames, there are actually 136 unique WWPN/alias tuples, which means that (136-112) 24 of the WWPNs have the same alias as other WWPNs</para>

<para>-i|&#8211;input import an existing JSON file for later editing </para>

<para>-r|&#8211;read import an existing JSON file for later editing </para>

<para><programlisting>java&#32;-jar&#32;vw4tools.jar&#32;--read&#32;working.json&#32;
</programlisting></para>

<para>-R|&#8211;remove Parse ncknames for removal from the internal nickname list </para>

<para>-R|&#8211;removenicknames Parse ncknames for removal from the internal nickname list</para>

<para>-!|&#8211;report Summarize the current status of the internal nicknaes and pattern/collation coverage </para>

<para><programlisting>java&#32;-jar&#32;vw4tools.jar&#32;--nickname=switch44.zoneshow&#32;&#32;--report
(vw4tools)&#32;parsed&#32;0&#32;zones,&#32;2&#32;aliases&#32;via&#32;Alias4Parser
vw4tools&#32;0.9-91
&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;5&#32;total&#32;entities
&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;4&#32;leaf&#32;nodes
&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;2&#32;orphans
50.00&#32;%&#32;coverage&#32;
</programlisting> </para>

<para>-P|&#8211;pattern= is used to provide an &quot;aggregating pattern&quot; to collect Orphan Entities into a container. An &quot;Orphan Entity&quot; is an entity which is not part of a larger device: an HBA not assigned to a host, or a FA not assigned to a storage array. Aggregating Patterns are evaluated immediately, so their order amidst other command options to import or remove entities is important. </para>
</listitem></varlistentry>
</variablelist>
</para>

</chapter>
